TSentralnyi soiuz ukraïnskoho studentstva. Records, 1922-1961 (inclusive), 1945-1958 (bulk): A Finding Aid.
Records, 1922-1961 (inclusive), 1945-1958 (bulk).
Ukrainian Research Institute Library, Harvard University
HOLLIS 009838854
TSentralnyi soiuz ukraïnskoho studentstva.
6 boxes (5.5 linear ft.)
Records of the Central Union of Ukrainian Students (TseSUS). This collection forms one part of the Ukrainian Student Movement Archive.
Access is by appointment only. Contact the Institute Bibliographer/Archivist.
Established in Prague in 1922, the Central Union of Ukrainian Students (TseSUS) was organized to act as a coordinating body between student organizations outside the Soviet Union and to represent Ukrainian students and their interests throughout the world. From 1922 to 1934, TseSUS headquarters were in Prague, and from 1934 to 1939 in Vienna. Membership included a number of national student unions based in Romania, Poland, Germany, as well as individual students' clubs abroad in other European countries, North America and Asia (Harbin). TseSUS was active in the international forum, informing non-Ukrainians about problems of Ukrainian students and about conditions in Ukraine in general under the different occupations. To maintain an effective relationship with non-Ukrainian organizations, TseSUS appointed representations in various countries. It participated in international student organizations, sent delegates to their conferences, collaborated with numerous national student unions, and published materials in foreign languages. The organization was a special member of the Confédération Internationale des Etudiants (later replaced by the International Union of Students), and a member of the aid organization the International Students' Service. TseSUS resumed its activities in Munich in 1946, and remained based there (except for a brief time when its head office was in Paris from 1952 to 1954) until its move to the United States. The early post-world war years were marked by resurgent organized student activity, with the union representing in 1947 at its peak 33 student organizations in ten countries with a total membership of nearly 3,000. The organization remained active until the early 1950s when many students living in Western Europe graduated and immigrated to North America.
Organized in five series:
I. Congresses
II. Administration
A. Presidium (Executive and Secretariat)
B. Departments
III. Divisions and representatives
IV. Member societies
V. Publications
A. TseSUS
B. Member clubs and societies
The material contains correspondence, minutes, and other materials related to the All-Student Founding Congress of 1945, as well as from the 11th to the 18th Ordinary Congresses of TseSUS. There are also administrative records from the Executive, Secretariat, and Departments of the organization. This material includes early correspondence from the 1920s and 1930s regarding the founding of TseSUS, with the bulk of the material comprised of administrative correspondence, circulars, minutes, reports, and student questionnaires from 1945 to 1955. Other administrative documents are from the departments of Culture and Education, Social Welfare, and International Affairs. The records of TseSUS also contain correspondence from its divisions and representatives in various countries such as Germany, Austria, Switzerland, the Netherlands, Belgium, and the United States, as well as from member societies, including the Obnova Society of Ukrainian Catholic Students, the Alliance of Ukrainian Orthodox Students, and Ukrainian student societies in Geneva, Zurich, Rome, Paris, Galway, and Stockholm. TseSUS, its divisions, and member societies are also documented in their various internal and student publications, as, for example, Studentskyi shliakh and the bulletin Visnyk TseSUSu.
For other collections comprising the Ukrainian Student Movement Archive see:
Records of the Union of Ukrainian Student Associations in Germany (SUSON)
Records of the Federation of Ukrainian Student Organizations of America (SUSTA)
- I. Congresses ([Box 1])
  - All-Student Founding Congress (25-27 Dec. 1945)--minutes, 1945
  - 11th Ordinary Congress (21-22 July 1946, Munich)--minutes, 1946
  - Congress of Ukrainian Student Clubs (16 Mar. 1947, Munich), 1946-1947
  - Congresses--lists of attendees, 1946-1947
  - 4th Extraordinary Congress (28 June 1947, Munich)--minutes, 1947
  - 12th Ordinary Congress (29-30 June 1947, Munich)--correspondence, 1947
  - 12th Ordinary Congress (29-30 June 1947, Munich)--minutes, 1947
  - Congresses--materials, 1948
  - 14th Ordinary Congress (9-10 Oct. 1948, Munich)--minutes, 1948
  - 14th Ordinary Congress (9-10 Oct. 1948, Munich)--delegates, 1948
  - Student Ideological Congress (15-17 May 1948, Munich)--speeches, 1948
  - 15th Ordinary Congress (25-26 Aug. 1949, Munich)--minutes, 1949
  - 15th Ordinary Congress (25-26 Aug. 1949, Munich)--materials, 1949
  - Ordinary Congress (20 June 1950, not held), 1949-1950
  - 16th Ordinary Congress (28-30 Dec. 1951, Louvain)--invitations, 1951
  - 16th Ordinary Congress (14-20 Dec. 1951, Louvain)--greetings, 1951-1952
  - 17th Ordinary Congress (22-23 Aug. 1953, Paris), 1953
  - 17th Ordinary Congress (22-23 Aug. 1953, Paris), 1953
  - 18th Ordinary Congress (2-4 Aug. 1954, London), 1954
- II. Administration
  - A. Presidium (Executive and Secretariat) ([Boxes 1, 2, 3])
    - History--clippings, correspondence, CEDUS, NOUS, 1922-1953 ([Box 1])
    - English archive, 1933 ([Box 1])
    - French archive, 1933-1934 ([Box 1])
    - Hungarian archive, 1933-1935 ([Box 1])
    - German archive, 1933-1936 ([Box 1])
    - Statutes, 1937, 1947 ([Box 1])
    - Register of correspondence (rec. and sent), 1939-1940 ([Box 1])
    - Provisional All-Student Initiative Committee--materials, 1945 ([Box 1])
    - Provisional All-Student Initiative Committee--registers of correspondence, 1945 ([Box 1])
    - Register of correspondence (rec.), 1945-1946 ([Box 1])
    - Executive--minutes, 1945-1947 ([Box 1])
    - Executive--correspondence (rec.), 1946 ([Box 1])
    - Executive--correspondence (sent), 1946 ([Box 1])
    - Register of correspondence (sent), 1946 ([Box 1])
    - Academic mentorship, 1946 ([Box 1])
    - Ukrainian Student Clubs--reports to the Executive, 1946 ([Box 1])
    - Lists of students in need of financial and material assistance, 1946 ([Box 1])
    - Student questionnaires, 1946 ([Box 1])
    - Student questionnaires, 1946-1947 ([Box 1])
    - Executive--correspondence (rec.), 1946-1947 ([Box 1])
    - Executive--correspondence from Ukrainian student clubs (rec.), 1946-1947 ([Box 1])
    - Executive--minutes, 1946-1947 ([Box 1])
    - Ukrainian Students' Aid Commission--minutes, 1946-1947 ([Box 1])
    - Ukrainian Student Clubs--information cards, 1946-1949 ([Box 1])
    - Departmental and divisional reports, 1946-1951 ([Box 2])
    - Notices, 1946-1953 ([Box 2])
    - Circulars, 1946-1953 ([Box 2])
    - Powers of attorney, 1947 ([Box 2])
    - Resolutions, 1947 ([Box 2])
    - Executive--organizational chart, 1947 ([Box 2])
    - Informational bulletins, 1947 ([Box 2])
    - 3rd Meeting of TseSUS--departmental reports, 1947 ([Box 2])
    - All-Student Coordinating Commission--correspondence and minutes, 1947 ([Box 2])
    - All-Student Coordinating Commission--minutes (27 June 1947), 1947 ([Box 2])
    - Executive--minutes, 1947-1948 ([Box 2])
    - Executive--minutes, 1947-1948 ([Box 2])
    - Executive--minutes, 1947-1948 ([Box 2])
    - Ukrainian Welfare, Education and Employment Organization of the British Zone in Germany, 1947-1948 ([Box 2])
    - Misc., 1947-1948 ([Box 2])
    - Student questionnaires, 1947-1948 ([Box 2])
    - Executive--correspondence (rec. from members of the Executive Board), 1947-1949 ([Box 2])
    - Executive--correspondence (rec. from divisions), 1947-1949 ([Box 2])
    - Executive--regulations, 1947-1949 ([Box 2])
    - Executive--correspondence (rec. from organizations), 1947-1949 ([Box 2])
    - Executive--correspondence (rec. from individuals and other organizations), 1947-1949 ([Box 2])
    - Ukrainian Students' Aid Commission--correspondence and minutes, 1947-1949 ([Box 2])
    - Circulars, 1948 ([Box 2])
    - Directory of forwarded applications, 1948 ([Box 2])
    - Executive--minutes, 1948-1949 ([Box 2])
    - Executive--minutes, 1948-1949 ([Box 2])
    - Ukrainian Students' Aid Commission--correspondence (rec.), 1948-1949 ([Box 2])
    - Ukrainian Students' Aid Commission, 1948-1951 ([Box 2])
    - Circulars (rec.), 1948, 1952 ([Box 2])
    - Register of correspondence, 1949
    - Students'kyi visnyk--list of mailed issues, 1949 ([Box 2])
    - Ukrainian Students' Aid Commission--address book of Ukrainian organizations, 1949 ([Box 2])
    - World Congress of Ukrainian Youth, 1949 ([Box 2])
    - Histories of student organizations, 1949-1951 ([Box 2])
    - Executive--correspondence (rec.), 1949-1951 ([Box 2])
    - Executive--correspondence, 1949-1952 ([Box 2])
    - Misc., 1949-1952 ([Box 2])
    - World Congress of Ukrainian Youth--correspondence, 1950 ([Box 2])
    - World Student Service Fund--directory of stipends to Ukrainian students, 1950 ([Box 2])
    - Relief and Emigration Committee of Foreign Students in Germany, 1950-1951 ([Box 2])
    - Departmental reports, 1950-1951 ([Box 2])
    - Misc., 1950-1951 ([Box 2])
    - Misc., 1950-1951 ([Box 3])
    - Articles, 1950-1951 ([Box 3])
    - Executive--minutes, 1950-1952 ([Box 3])
    - Misc., 1950-1959 ([Box 3])
    - Misc., 1950-1964 ([Box 3])
    - Reports (misc.), 1951 ([Box 3])
    - International Delegates Commission--questionnaires, 1951 ([Box 3])
    - European Students' Congress in Berlin (14-17 May 1951)--materials, 1951 ([Box 3])
    - Conference in Berlin (18-20 Aug. 1951)--report, 1951 ([Box 3])
    - Union mondiale des étudiants juifs, 1951 ([Box 3])
    - Reports, 1951, 1953 ([Box 3])
    - Informational bulletins (rec.), 1951-1954 ([Box 3])
    - Circulars, 1951-1955 ([Box 3])
    - Executive--correspondence (sent), 1952 ([Box 3])
    - Executive--correspondence, 1952-1953 ([Box 3])
    - Executive--plenary meetings, 1952-1953 ([Box 3])
    - Executive--minutes, 1952-1953 ([Box 3])
    - General Secretary--reports, 1952-1953 ([Box 3])
    - Secretariat--correspondence with student organizations and representatives, 1952-1953 ([Box 3])
    - Secretariat--registers of correspondence (rec. and sent), 1952-1953 ([Box 3])
    - Secretariat--clippings, 1952-1953 ([Box 3])
    - Secretariat--Ukrainian Students' Aid Commission, 1952-1953 ([Box 3])
    - Secretariat--misc. Ukrainian organizations, 1952-1953 ([Box 3])
    - Secretariat--Ukrainian Congress Committee in New York, 1952-1953 ([Box 3])
    - Misc., 1952-1953 ([Box 3])
    - Misc. reports, 1952-1953 ([Box 3])
    - Third International Student Conference in Copenhagen--report by TseSUS delegates, 1953 ([Box 3])
    - Student questionnaires, 1953 ([Box 3])
    - Executive--correspondence, 1953-1954 ([Box 3])
    - Executive--correspondence (rec.), 1953-1954 ([Box 3])
    - Circulars, 1953-1954 ([Box 3])
    - General Secretary--minutes, 1953-1954 ([Box 3])
    - Secretariat--expenditures, 1953-1954 ([Box 3])
    - Secretariat--correspondence (sent), 1953-1954 ([Box 3])
    - Executive--minutes, 1954-1955 ([Box 3])
    - Executive--minutes, 1954-1956 ([Box 3])
    - Vsevolod Mardak--correspondence, 1954-1957 ([Box 3])
    - Presidium--correspondence (rec.), 1955 ([Box 3])
    - President--correspondence (rec.), 1956 ([Box 3])
    - Executive--correspondence (rec.), 1956 ([Box 3])
    - Secretariat--correspondence (rec.), 1956 ([Box 3])
    - Ukrainian Students' Aid Commission--misc., 1960 ([Box 3])
    - Smoloskyp: re. future of TseSUS, 1960 ([Box 3])
    - Questionnaire, n.d. ([Box 3])
    - Speech, n.d. ([Box 3])
    - Articles re. Ukrainian student organizations, n.d. ([Box 3])
    - Misc. (2 folders), n.d. ([Box 3])
    - Photographs:
      - Kuban Cossacks, n.d. ([Box 3])
      - Representation of Ukrainian Student Societies in Austria (PUSTA), n.d. ([Box 3])
      - Federation of Ukrainian Student Organization of America, Aug. 1957 ([Box 3])
      - TseSUS, n.d. ([Box 3])
      - TseSUS, n.d. ([Box 3])
      - Tsesus (Rotterdam), May 23, 1948 ([Box 3])
      - Bilyk, Markiian, n.d. ([Box 3])
      - Butrynskyi, M., n.d. ([Box 3])
      - Dvirnyk, Osyp, n.d. ([Box 3])
      - Koszyk, Mykola, n.d. ([Box 3])
      - Kupranets, Franko, n.d. ([Box 3])
      - Lisovskyi, Petro, n.d. ([Box 3])
      - Lytwyn, Petro, n.d. ([Box 3])
      - Pryima, Vasyl, n.d. ([Box 3])
      - Rozumnyj, Jaroslav, n.d. ([Box 3])
      - Sawka, Augustyn, n.d. ([Box 3])
      - Szarakewycz, Wolodymyr, n.d. ([Box 3])
      - Vyzhak, Teodor, n.d. ([Box 3])
      - Unidentified negatives, n.d. ([Box 3])
  - B. Departments ([Boxes 3, 4])
    - Culture and Education Department--correspondence, 1946 ([Box 3])
    - Culture and Education Department--misc., 1946 ([Box 3])
    - Finance Department, 1946-1948 ([Box 3])
    - Culture and Education Department--circulars and correspondence, 1947-1948 ([Box 3])
    - Culture and Education Department--agenda, 1947-1948 ([Box 3])
    - Culture and Education Department--re: union of schools of higher education, 1947-1948 ([Box 3])
    - Social Welfare Department--correspondence, 1947-1950 ([Box 3])
    - Auditing Committee, 1947, 1952 ([Box 3])
    - Culture and Education Department--student handbook, 1948 ([Box 3])
    - Culture and Education Department--annotations to documents, 1948 ([Box 3])
    - Culture and Education Department--research on student thought, 1948 ([Box 3])
    - Culture and Education Department--research on student thought, 1948 ([Box 3])
    - International Affairs Department--correspondence, 1948-1949 ([Box 3])
    - International Affairs Department--reports, 1949 ([Box 3])
    - International Affairs Department--correspondence, 1949 ([Box 3])
    - International Affairs Department--correspondence (rec.), 1949-1951 ([Box 4])
    - International Affairs Department--correspondence (sent), 1950 ([Box 4])
    - International Affairs Department--correspondence (sent), 1950 ([Box 4])
    - International Affairs Department, 1950-1951 ([Box 4])
    - International Affairs Department--register of correspondence (sent), 1951-1952 ([Box 4])
    - Culture and Education Department--correspondence, 1951-1955 ([Box 4])
    - International Affairs Department--reports, 1951-1958 ([Box 4])
    - Administrative Department--correspondence (sent), 1952 ([Box 4])
    - Social Welfare Department--reports, 1952-1953 ([Box 4])
    - Administrative Department--correspondence (rec.), 1952-1953 ([Box 4])
    - Culture and Education Department--Ukrainian students in foreign countries, 1953-1954 ([Box 4])
    - Administrative Department--correspondence (sent), 1953-1956 ([Box 4])
    - International Affairs Department--correspondence, 1954-1956 ([Box 4])
    - Press Department, 1955
    - Culture and Education Department--correspondence (sent), 1955 ([Box 4])
    - International Affairs Department, 1955 ([Box 4])
    - Culture and Education Department--correspondence (sent), 1955-1956 ([Box 4])
    - Finance Department--correspondence (rec.), 1956 ([Box 4])
    - Administrative Department--correspondence (sent), 1956-1958 ([Box 4])
    - Administrative Department--correspondence (rec.), 1957-1958 ([Box 4])
- III. Divisions and Representatives ([Box 4])
  - Representation of the American Zone in Munich, Germany-- correspondence (sent), 1946-1947
  - Representation of the American Zone in Munich, Germany--account book, 1946-1947
  - Representative in Switzerland--correspondence, 1946-1949
  - Representative in the Netherlands, 1946-1947
  - Belgian Division--correspondence (sent), 1947-1948
  - Belgian Division--minutes of the Executive Board, 1947-1948
  - Representation of Ukrainian Student Societies in Austria--correspondence (sent), 1947-1949
  - Representation of Ukrainian Student Societies in Austria--correspondence (rec.), 1947-1949
  - Belgian Division--register of correspondence (sent), 1948
  - Belgian Division--register of correspondence (sent), 1948
  - Belgian Division--correspondence, 1948
  - Representative in the Netherlands--correspondence (rec.), 1951-1953
  - American division--correspondence, 1952
  - American Division, 1952-1959
  - American Division--correspondence, 1953
  - Representative in Ireland, 1953-1954
  - Representative in Canada, 1953-1958
  - Representative in Norway, 1954-1955
  - Representative in Brazil, 1954-1958
  - American Division--correspondence (rec.), 1957-1958
- IV. Member Societies ([Boxes 4, 5])
  - Ukraina Student Society in Geneva--financial material, 1929-1934 ([Box 4])
  - Ukraina Student Society in Geneva--register of correspondence, 1930-1936 ([Box 4])
  - Ukraina Student Society in Geneva--correspondence (rec.), 1930-1938 ([Box 4])
  - Ukraina Student Society in Geneva--correspondence (sent), 1932-1935 ([Box 4])
  - Ukrainian Student Club in Rome, 1946 ([Box 4])
  - Ukrainian Student Club in Rimini, 1946 ([Box 4])
  - Ukrainian Academic Hromada in Bern, 1946-1947 ([Box 4])
  - National Union of Ukrainian Students in Belgium, 1946-1952 ([Box 4])
  - Obnova Society of Ukrainian Catholic Students in Munich, 1947-1949 ([Box 4])
  - Obnova Society of Ukrainian Catholic Students in Madrid, 1947-1952 ([Box 4])
  - Obnova Society of Ukrainian Catholic Students--Pax Romana assembly, 1948 ([Box 4])
  - Ukrainian Academic League of Social Humanism, 1948 ([Box 4])
  - Alliance of Ukrainian Orthodox Students--minutes, 1948-1949
  - Obnova Society of Ukrainian Catholic Students in Munich--minutes, 1948-1949 ([Box 4])
  - Obnova Society of Ukrainian Catholic Students--reports, 1948-1950
  - Alliance of Ukrainian Orthodox Students--correspondence (sent), 1949 ([Box 4])
  - Alliance of Ukrainian Orthodox Students--correspondence (rec.), 1949 ([Box 4])
  - Alliance of Ukrainian Orthodox Students--correspondence, 1949-1954 ([Box 4])
  - Ukrainian Student Club in Paris, 1949-1955 ([Box 4])
  - Ukrainian Academic Hromada in Bern--correspondence, 1950 ([Box 5])
  - Ukrainian Student Club in Zurich--correspondence, 1950-1953 ([Box 5])
  - Ukrainian Academic Club in Stockholm--report, 1951 ([Box 5])
  - Ukrainian Student Club in Paris--correspondence and minutes, 1951-1953 ([Box 5])
  - Ukrainian Student Club in Galway--reports, 1951-1953 ([Box 5])
  - Association of Ukrainian Students in Great Britain--correspondence, 1951-1953 ([Box 5])
  - Ukrainian Academic Club in Stockholm--correspondence, 1952-1953 ([Box 5])
  - National Union of Ukrainian Students in Belgium--correspondence, 1952-1953 ([Box 5])
  - Obnova Society of Ukrainian Catholic Students in Madrid--correspondence, 1952-1953 ([Box 5])
  - Ukrainian Student Club in Zurich--correspondence, 1952-1953 ([Box 5])
  - Ukrainian ideological student organizations--correspondence, 1952-1953 ([Box 5])
  - Sich student society of Grats, Austria, 1952-1958 ([Box 5])
  - Ukrainian Student Club in Cleveland, Ohio, 1953 ([Box 5])
  - Ukrainian Canadian Students' Union--Preparatory Committee for the Regional Congress, 1953 ([Box 5])
  - Ukrainian Student Association in Montreal, Canada, 1953-1954 ([Box 5])
  - Association of Ukrainian Students in Great Britain, 1953-1958 ([Box 5])
  - National Union of Ukrainian Students in Belgium, 1953-1958 ([Box 5])
  - Ukrainian Academic Hromada in Switzerland, 1954 ([Box 5])
  - Ukrainian Student Association in Innsbruck, 1954-1955 ([Box 5])
  - Ukrainian Student Club in Rome, 1954-1955 ([Box 5])
  - Ukrainian Academic Club in Stockholm, 1954-1958 ([Box 5])
  - National Union of Ukrainian Student Organizations in Germany, 1954-1958 ([Box 5])
  - Ukrainian Student Club in Paris, 1954-1958 ([Box 5])
  - Obnova Society of Ukrainian Catholic Students in Madrid, 1954-1958 ([Box 5])
  - Union of Argentinean-Ukrainian Students, 1954-1958 ([Box 5])
  - Federation of Ukrainian Student Organization of America, 1954-1958 ([Box 5])
  - Ukrainian Canadian Students' Union, 1954-1958 ([Box 5])
  - Ukrainian Student Club in Southern Australia, 1954-1958 ([Box 5])
  - Federation of Ukrainian Student Organizations of America--report of the 21st Ordinary Congress (21 Sep. 1957, Paris), 1957 ([Box 5])
  - Ukrainian Student Club in Vienna, 1958 ([Box 5])
- V. Publications ([Box 5])
  - A. TseSUS
    - TseSUS: 1908-1918-1938. V Rokovyny: ukrains'ke studentstvo v mynulomu i suchasnomu, 1938
    - Biuleten' TseSUSa (Vienna), 1939
    - Students'kyi shliakh (Innsbruck-Munich), 1945-1947
    - Za pravoporiadok students'koho seredovyshcha (Innsbruck-Munich), 1946
    - Korotkyi informator pry vysoki shkoly v Nimechchyni (Munich), 1946
    - Visnyk: orhan rosporiadkiv' ta postanov TseSUSa (Munich), 1946
    - Zveno: literatura, mystetstvo, krytyka (Innsbruck), 1946
    - Students'kyi shliakh --manuscripts, 1947
    - Students'kyi zbirnyk: zhurnal TseSUS-a (Munich), 1947
    - Informatyvnyi biuleten', 1947-1948
    - Students'kyi visnyk: zhurnal TseSUSa (Munich), 1947-1948
    - Visti TseSUSa (Munich), 1947-49, 1951-55
    - L'Etudiant ukrainien: bulletin d'information de l'Union centrale des etudiants ukrainiens, 1952-1954
    - Smoloskyp: anketnyi lystok vidnosno TseSUS, 1960
    - Misc. publications and brochures, n.d.
  - B. Member clubs and societies
    - Obnova: biuleten' tovarystv Ukrains'kykh Studentiv Katolykiv (Louvain), 1948, 1955-1957
    - Visti Akademichnoi Hromady im. Shevchenka v Shvaitsarii (Bern), 1949
    - Svitanok: iuvileine vyd. Ob'iednannia Ukrains'kykh Pravoslavnykh Studentiv (Munich), 1949
    - Obizhnyk: Federatsiia Tovarystv Ukrains'kykh Studentiv Katolykiv Obnova (Munich), 1949-1950
    - Zarevo: biuleten' (Munich), 1949-1951
    - Informatsiinyi lystok Literaturnoi Komisii. Ob'iednannia Ukrains'kykh Students'kykh Tovarystv National'noho Solidaryzmu Zarevo (Munich), 1950
    - Informatsiinyi biuleten' T-va Ukrains'koi Studiuiuchoi Molodi im. M. Mikhnovs'koho (Munich), 1950, 1952, 1954
    - Iunist': lystok Literaturnoi Komisii Zarevo (Munich-Montreal), 1951
    - Finisterre: informatyvnyi periodyk TUSK Obnova (Madrid), 1956-1958
    - Informatsiinyi lystok: Natsional'nyi Soiuz Ukrains'kykh Studentiv u Bel'hii (Louvain), 1957
    - Students'ke zhyttia: organo de la Unión de Estudiantes Argentino Ucranios1959-1961 (Buenos Aires)